Workplace Competition Code
직장 경쟁 코드
(The characters, events, groups, organizations and backgrounds of this drama are purely fictitious. We hereby inform you that)
(본 드라마에 등장하는 인물, 사건, 단체, 조직, 배경 등은 순전히 허구입니다. 이를 알려드립니다.)
I want to expose the domineering and oppressive behavior of the big company Se Yong
대기업 세용의 폭압적이고 폭압적인 행위를 폭로하고 싶다
Doesn't Serong have a message board to listen to customers' voices?
세롱 에는 고객의 소리를 들을 수 있는 게시판이 없나요 ?
Something big happened there now
지금 거기서 큰 일이 일어났어
Some people say they want to expose the inside story of Shirong's bullying.
어떤 사람들은 시롱이 괴롭힘을 당한 내막을 폭로하고 싶다고 말합니다.
He also said that the person in charge, Park Yoon-soo,
또 박윤수 담당자가 말했다.
His career was ruined and even his employees fell down.
그의 경력은 망가졌고 직원들마저 쓰러졌습니다.
So is this true?
그렇다면 이것이 사실인가요?
right
오른쪽
You deliberately disparage other companies' products
의도적으로 다른 회사의 제품을 폄하하는 경우
Fabricating false information and spreading it, right?
허위사실을 조작해서 퍼뜨리는거 맞죠?
Please answer me, Agent Park Yun-soo
대답해주세요 박윤수 요원님
right
오른쪽
Team Leader Chi Yinzhen, did you know this already?
Chi Yinzhen 팀장님, 이미 알고 계셨나요?
Representative Park Yoon-soo, the person in charge
담당자 박윤수 대표
Please tell me what happened so far
지금까지 무슨 일이 있었는지 말해주세요
Write a report in detail and give it to me
보고서를 구체적으로 작성해서 건네주세요
You must write the truth, no lies
거짓이 아닌 진실을 써야 한다
Understand?
이해하다?
Understand? Agent Park Yun-soo
이해하다? 박윤수 요원
yes
예
There are three more groups
세 그룹이 더 있어요
If it is discovered that your entire group was involved
귀하의 그룹 전체가 관련되어 있는 것으로 밝혀진 경우
Then it’s not just Park Yoon-soo’s agent
그렇다면 박윤수 에이전트만이 아니다.
Your entire group may be disbanded.
귀하의 그룹 전체가 해체될 수 있습니다.
I hope you take this matter seriously
이 문제를 진지하게 받아들이길 바랍니다
Your unanswered call will be forwarded to...
부재중 전화는 다음으로 전달됩니다...
(Masaaki)
(允昭)
That brat...
그 놈...
What are you doing? Why can't I get through the company phone?
뭐하세요? 왜 회사 전화로 연결이 안 되나요?
We unplugged the phone lines
우리는 전화선을 뽑았습니다
Reporters have also learned the news
기자들도 이 소식을 접했습니다.
Since when did they care so much about Shi Yong's discussion forum?
언제부터 시용 토론장에 그토록 관심을 가졌던 걸까요?
It really scared me to death
정말 무서워 죽겠어요
Maybe it’s because something happened on the social platform that I represented before .
어쩌면 제가 예전에 대표했던 소셜 플랫폼 에서 무슨 일이 일어났기 때문일지도 모르겠습니다.
Anyway, reporters kept calling like crazy.
어쨌든 기자들은 미친 듯이 계속 전화를 걸었다.
Team leader Song asked us to unplug the phone line.
송 팀장은 우리에게 전화선을 뽑아달라고 요청했습니다.
How is Yun Zhao doing?
자오윤은 잘 지내요?
- How are you, Agent Park? - She is your friend, why are you asking me?
- 잘 지내세요, 박요원님? - 그 사람은 네 친구인데 왜 나한테 묻는 거야?
Because she doesn't listen to my calls
그 사람은 내 전화를 듣지 않으니까
Director Goo came down early in the morning
구 감독님이 아침 일찍 내려오셨어요.
He scolded us
그는 우리를 꾸짖었다
Hey, do you know?
이봐, 그거 알아?
In fact, this is not the first time we have done negative marketing.
사실 우리가 네거티브 마케팅을 한 것은 이번이 처음은 아니다.
It's just that everyone comes secretly
그냥 다들 몰래 오는 것 뿐이야
But Director Goo suddenly became furious this time, so no one dared to say anything.
그런데 이번에는 구 감독이 갑자기 화를 내서 누구도 감히 말을 하지 못했다.
- I asked you how Yun Zhao is doing - Yun Zhao?
- 윤자오 씨는 잘 지내냐고 물었어요. - 윤자오 씨는요?
Are you only worried about your friends?
친구들만 걱정하시나요?
She's not the only problem
그 사람만이 문제가 아니죠
The entire three groups may be disbanded
3개 그룹 전체가 해체될 수도 있다
Hey, have you read the article in the discussion forum?
안녕하세요, 토론 포럼에 있는 기사를 읽어보셨나요?
If you watch, you will know that Agent Park is basically a traitor
보시면 아시겠지만 박요원은 기본적으로 배신자입니다.
The other party's accomplice was hospitalized and the store could hardly continue to operate.
상대방 공범이 병원에 입원해 가게 운영이 거의 불가능해졌습니다.
so what?
그래서 뭐?
Are they planning to frame everything on Agent Park this time too?
이번에도 Agent Park의 모든 것을 구성할 계획 인가요?
- What? - The actual person in charge is Shin Ji-hyo
- 무엇? - 실제 담당자는 신지효입니다.
The team leaders and the sales team all know about this.
팀장, 영업팀 모두 이 사실을 알고 있습니다.
Both the third group and the second group participated.
세 번째 그룹과 두 번째 그룹이 모두 참여했습니다.
But who would know this?
하지만 누가 이것을 알겠습니까?
After all, the name of the person in charge on the document is Park Yoon-soo.
결국 해당 문서의 책임자 이름은 박윤수다.
That's how things will turn out
상황은 그렇게 되겠죠
But are you angry at me now?
그런데 지금 나한테 화난 거야?
I know, let's do this first
알겠어, 우선 이것부터 하자
Why is he angry with me?
그 사람은 왜 나에게 화를 내는 걸까요?
(Masaaki)
(允昭)
(Jae Min)
(재민)
There is no response to the number you called. Please wait after the beep...
전화하신 번호는 응답이 없습니다. 삐 소리가 난 후 기다려주세요...
Call me when you're fine
괜찮으면 전화해
I have something to go to Changwon now.
지금 창원에 갈 일이 있어요.
Will go back today
오늘은 돌아갈 거야
It doesn't matter, no one thought he would upload that kind of article
상관없어, 그 사람이 그런 글을 올릴 거라고는 아무도 생각 못 했어
- Senior - Yes
- 선배 - 예
About the Shi Yong discussion forum...
Shi Yong 토론 포럼에 대해...
I know, I've heard it
알아요, 들어본 적 있어요
Didn't Yun Zhao come to the company yesterday?
어제 자오윤이 회사에 안 왔어요?
yesterday
어제
Director An said
안 원장은 이렇게 말했다.
She found that she didn't take something, so she went back to the office
그녀는 자신이 아무것도 가져가지 않은 것을 알고 사무실로 돌아갔습니다.
Maybe that's when she heard that Se Yong did it.
아마도 그때 세용이가 그런 짓을 했다는 말을 들었을 것이다.
So it was Chief An who told the truth?
그렇다면 진실을 말한 사람은 안과장이었던 걸까.
She only told me
그녀는 나에게만 말했어
She came and asked me what to do
그녀가 와서 나에게 무엇을 해야할지 물었습니다
But this matter was raised by the ginger boss who sells high-protein bread.
그런데 이 문제는 고단백 빵을 파는 생강사장이 제기한 것이다.
heard by chance
우연히 들린
I didn't expect him to post an article in the discussion forum
나는 그가 토론 포럼에 글을 올릴 것이라고는 예상하지 못했습니다.
Where is Yun Zhao? Have you contacted her?
자오윤은 어디에 있나요? 그 사람한테 연락해봤어?
have
가지다
She came yesterday to ask what she should do
그녀는 어제 와서 무엇을 해야 하는지 물었습니다
She said she couldn't stop it
그녀는 그것을 멈출 수 없다고 말했다
But I can't stand by and watch
하지만 가만히 서서 지켜볼 수는 없어
this…
이것…
Although overall it’s Se Yong’s problem
전체적으로는 세용이의 문제지만
But what I'm worried about is
그런데 제가 걱정되는 건
They'll find a scapegoat to cover it up
그들은 그것을 은폐할 희생양을 찾을 것이다
I'm more worried that that person will be Yun Zhao
그 사람이 윤자오일까봐 더 걱정된다
I'm here to find her, tell me
난 그녀를 찾으러 여기 있어요, 말해 보세요
I just want to say a few words to you
나는 단지 당신에게 몇 마디 말하고 싶습니다.
Didn't you ask me what I plan to do next?
내가 앞으로 무엇을 할 계획인지 묻지 않았나요?
He also asked me how to run the company like this
회사를 이렇게 운영하려면 어떻게 해야 하냐고 묻기도 하더군요.
How can we continue to sit in the representative seat?
우리가 어떻게 계속해서 대표 자리에 앉을 수 있을까요?
represent
대표하다
I want to tell you that the current public opinion about Se Yong is very bad.
현재 세용에 대한 여론이 매우 좋지 않다는 점을 말씀드리고 싶습니다 .
I think this is all because we lack a strategy chief
이게 다 전략 책임자가 부족해서 그런 것 같아요
The Public Relations Office is affiliated to the Strategy Headquarters
홍보실은 전략본부 산하
Now the department is missing a head
이제 부서에는 책임자가 없습니다.
What exactly is going on?
정확히 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
I'm still figuring out the truth
난 아직도 진실을 알아가는 중이야
So what are you going to do after clarifying the truth?
그럼 진상을 밝히고 나면 어떻게 하시겠습니까?
If they really did something wrong they should apologize
정말 잘못했다면 사과해야지
and assume corresponding responsibilities
그리고 상응하는 책임을 맡는다
Did you hear that?
그거 들었어?
They're not going to sit idly by and you're worrying too much
그들은 가만히 앉아 있지 않을 것이고 당신은 너무 걱정하고 있습니다.
Employees who keep causing disputes are indeed problematic
계속 말다툼을 하는 직원은 정말 문제다.
But organizations that leave their employees alone are also problematic.
하지만 직원을 내버려두는 조직도 문제가 있다.
So it's not just that employee.
그럼 그 직원뿐만이 아니군요.
The head of the organization to which the employee belongs cannot escape responsibility.
해당 직원이 속한 조직의 장은 책임을 면할 수 없습니다.
She didn't always cause strife
그녀는 늘 다툼을 일으키지는 않았어
But you're right
하지만 당신 말이 맞아요
As the head of the public relations office, of course I also have to take responsibility.
홍보실장으로서 책임도 당연히 져야죠.
I will take responsibility if necessary
필요하다면 책임지겠습니다
You must feel very happy
당신은 매우 행복감을 느낄 것입니다
After all you've heard everything you wanted to hear
결국 당신은 당신이 듣고 싶은 모든 것을 들었다
thank you for the tea
차 고마워요
(Representative Office)
(대표 사무소)
What will be served for lunch in the staff cafeteria today?
오늘 직원 식당에서 점심으로 무엇을 제공할까요?
Today it’s bean sprout soup and spicy stir-fried pork
오늘은 콩나물국과 매콤한 돼지고기 볶음입니다
Not bad
나쁘지 않다
Did the conversation go well just now?
방금 대화는 잘 됐나요?
Tell Director Zheng Shouhuan to get ready.
Zheng Shouhuan 감독에게 준비하라고 말하세요.
I will make a decision soon
조만간 결정을 내리겠습니다
Sorry, Vice President
죄송합니다, 부사장님
Although Director Zheng is a good talent,
정 감독은 좋은 재능을 갖고 있지만,
But Director Chen has also served in the public relations office for a long time.
하지만 첸 이사는 오랫동안 홍보실에서도 근무해왔습니다.
His loyalty is unmatched by anyone's
그의 충성심은 누구와도 비교할 수 없습니다
Don't decide so quickly
너무 빨리 결정하지 마세요
How about giving it a little more thought?
조금 더 생각해 보면 어떨까요?
Then do it this way
그럼 이렇게 해보세요
yes
예
What was that like just now?
지금은 어땠나요?
He's officially declared war on us, right?
그는 공식적으로 우리에게 전쟁을 선포했습니다. 그렇죠?
If this continues, I might be killed by him before I even draw my sword.
이대로라면 내가 검을 뽑기도 전에 그 사람에게 죽임을 당할 수도 있다.
If after investigation it turns out it was the PR office's fault
조사 결과 홍보실의 잘못으로 판명된 경우
I'm going to let Zheng Shouhuan take the position of head of the strategy department.
저는 Zheng Shouhuan 에게 전략 부서장 자리를 맡길 예정입니다 .
Then you will be kicked out immediately and become a beggar on the street.
그러면 즉시 쫓겨나 길거리의 거지가 될 것입니다.
Not only you and me, but also what is the name of that employee?
당신과 나뿐만 아니라 그 직원의 이름은 무엇입니까?
That's Park Yoon-so
바로 박윤소다.
That, Agent Park
그거, 박요원
How do you plan to write the report?
보고서는 어떻게 작성할 계획인가요?
Will you write it truthfully?
사실대로 쓰시겠어요?
Otherwise, how do you want me to write it?
그렇지 않으면 어떻게 쓰길 바라나요?
How should I write it? You say it, I will write it as you say
어떻게 써야 할까요? 당신이 말하니까 당신 말대로 쓸게요
(report)
(보고서)
(Affiliation: Business Strategy Headquarters Department: Public Relations Group 3, Position: Agent)
(소속 : 사업전략본부부 : 홍보3그룹, 직위 : Agent)
focus a little
조금 집중해
(Se Yong)
(세용)
Protein powder raw material supplier?
단백질 분말 원료 공급업체?
right
오른쪽
Did you upgrade the formula after changing suppliers?
공급업체를 변경한 후 제조법을 업그레이드했습니까?
The previous supplier was Dongxin, right?
이전 공급자는 Dongxin이었죠?
But I can't find information about the new supplier
그런데 새 공급업체에 대한 정보를 찾을 수 없습니다.
I heard it is a supplier called PF
PF라는 공급업체라고 들었는데
But I can't find the address of the factory
그런데 공장 주소를 못찾겠어요
I'm not sure about this
나는 이것에 대해 잘 모르겠습니다.
What?
무엇?
Aren't you the factory director? How could you not know?
공장장님 아니신가요? 어떻게 모를 수가 있니?
That's handled by the head office.
그건 본사에서 알아서 처리해줍니다.
Team leader Zhao said it was decided by the superiors.
팀 리더 Zhao는 상사가 결정했다고 말했습니다.
We are just collecting raw materials here
여기서는 그냥 원료를 모으고 있어요
(Whey protein isolate, produced in Denmark)
(덴마크산 분리유청단백질)
What about quality assurance?
품질 보증은 어떻습니까?
That's what Team Leader Zhao is handling too.
자오팀장도 그런 일을 하고 있다.
Previous supplier Dongxin
이전 공급업체 Dongxin
How are they doing now?
그들은 지금 어떻게 지내고 있나요?
Why do you ask this?
왜 이런 걸 물어보나요?
I really do not know
나는 정말로 모른다
Does the public relations office even need to know these things?
홍보실에서도 이런 것까지 알 필요가 있나요?
No
아니요
I'm just curious
그냥 궁금해서요
Then forget it
그럼 잊어버려
if there's anything else you want to tell me
나한테 또 하고 싶은 말이 있다면
this is for you
이건 널위한거야
(Agent, Public Relations Team 2, Liu Caimin)
(대리인 홍보2팀 유채민)
Just call my mobile number
그냥 내 휴대폰 번호로 전화해
good
좋은
(Se Yong)
(세용)
(report)
(보고서)
You haven't gotten off work yet
아직 퇴근 안 했잖아
sit down
앉아
Alas
아아
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
did you drink?
마 셨니?
I only drink a little
나는 조금만 마신다
You should have gone home after drinking. Why did you come back to the company again?
술 마시고 집에 갔어야 했는데 왜 다시 회사로 돌아왔나요?
this…
이것…
Anyway, no one will greet me when I get home.
어쨌든, 내가 집에 오면 아무도 나에게 인사하지 않을 것이다.
My wife and kids...
내 부인과 아이들...
Do you know Perth, Australia?
호주 퍼스를 아시나요?
Perth
퍼스
they live there
그들은 거기에 산다
We are a pretty typical family, right?
우리는 꽤 전형적인 가족이죠?
But they would move there not for their children’s studies.
그러나 그들은 자녀의 공부를 위해서가 아니라 그곳으로 이사하려고 했습니다.
It's because the child's atopic dermatitis is too severe
아이의 아토피 피부염이 너무 심해서 그렇습니다
They seemed happy to be able to live in that kind of place.
그런 곳에서 살 수 있어서 행복해 보였습니다.
You didn't ask that, right?
당신은 그런 걸 묻지 않았죠?
Recently, everyone says that this kind of behavior is called talking too much.
최근에는 이런 행동을 '말을 너무 많이 하는 것'이라고 다들 하잖아요.
But what do you want from me?
그런데 당신은 나에게 무엇을 원하는가?
I don’t think I saw Team Leader Chi this afternoon.
오늘 오후에는 치 팀장을 못 본 것 같아요.
She went out to work
그녀는 일하러 나갔다
She said she would get off work directly after it was over
일 끝나면 ​​바로 퇴근한다고 하더군요
It turns out she ran away
그녀가 도망친 것으로 밝혀졌습니다
so what?
그래서 뭐?
How do you plan to write the report?
보고서는 어떻게 작성할 계획인가요?
No matter how you write it, it will be a blow to Director Goo
어떻게 써도 구감독님 타격이겠죠
It feels like we gave our boss an uppercut
상사에게 어퍼컷을 준 것 같아
Why does the Council…
협의회는 왜…
Because some people are eagerly waiting for Director Goo to step down.
구 감독의 사퇴를 간절히 바라는 사람들도 있기 때문이다 .
Those people are waiting for an opportunity
그 사람들은 기회를 기다리고 있어
Keep an eye on her
그녀를 지켜보세요
that…
저것…
let me tell you
내가 말해주지
I'll give you some advice while you're drunk.
당신이 취한 동안 몇 가지 조언을 해줄게요.
You just…
방금…
Just think about yourself
그냥 너 자신에 대해 생각해봐
because
왜냐하면
No one will help you at all
아무도 당신을 전혀 도와주지 않을 거예요
so
그래서
Just protect yourself
그냥 자신을 보호
I'll figure it out myself
내가 직접 알아낼게
good
좋은
(report)
(보고서)
What do you want to drink?
무엇을 마시고 싶으십니까?
Tea? Or coffee?
차? 아니면 커피?
What?
무엇?
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
Not good, not good at all
좋지 않아, 전혀 좋지 않아
I'm just hanging on
난 그냥 매달리고 있어
Want to make instant coffee for you?
인스턴트 커피를 만들고 싶나요?
Would you like something sweet?
달콤한 것을 원하시나요?
OK
좋아요
Come
오다
Feel sorry
유감
I have to go somewhere today
오늘은 어디든 가야 해
I should have been with you
너와 함께 있었어야 했는데
what can I do for you?
내가 당신을 위해 무엇을 할 수?
Then lend it to me for a while.
그럼 잠시만 빌려주세요.
Just lend it to me for a while
잠시만 빌려주세요
I want to write a report but I don’t know how to write it
보고서를 쓰고 싶은데 어떻게 쓰는지 모르겠어요
Leader Song told me about this just now
방금 송 리더가 나한테 이런 얘기를 했어.
It will also deal a blow to Director Goo
구 감독에게도 타격이 될 듯
I'm also worried about our group
나도 우리 그룹이 걱정돼
You now
당신은 지금
Don't worry, Director Goo
걱정하지 마세요, 구 감독님
Don't worry about your group either.
당신의 그룹에 대해서도 걱정하지 마십시오.
Just think about yourself
그냥 너 자신에 대해 생각해봐
It doesn't matter if it's a little selfish
조금 이기적이라도 상관없어
Be stronger
더 강해지세요
you…
너…
Have you had dinner yet?
저녁은 먹었나요?
Have you got a meal yet?
식사는 아직 안 하셨나요?
Not yet, what's wrong? Do you want a treat?
아직은 아닙니다. 무슨 문제인가요? 당신은 치료를 원하십니까?
Why should I invite you?
내가 왜 당신을 초대해야 하나요?
It's not like you're not making money
돈을 못 버는 건 아니잖아
If you don't want a treat, then get out of here
대접을 원하지 않으면 여기서 나가세요
(Se Yong)
(세용)
Hello
안녕하세요
That, Director Goo
그거, 구 감독님
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
Here's what I think
내 생각은 이렇다
consider your position
당신의 입장을 고려하십시오
The internal culture improvement plan you are driving now
당신이 지금 추진하고 있는 내부문화 개선 방안
Is it too much?
너무 많은가요?
Why do you say that?
왜 그런 말을 해?
No, I'm just worried
아니, 그냥 걱정돼서 그래
You seem to have too much time to take care of yourself now
지금은 자기 자신을 돌볼 시간이 너무 많은 것 같아요
Such a flashy plan
이런 화려한 계획이라니
From the company's perspective, it's just spending money in vain with no benefit at all.
회사 입장에서는 아무런 이익도 없이 돈만 낭비하는 것입니다.
-Room Chief- Just give up now
-방장- 이제 그만 포기해
- I will not be embarrassed - Director Chen
- 부끄러워하지 않을게요 - 첸 감독
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
I'm not too busy to take care of myself now
지금은 너무 바빠서 내 자신을 돌볼 여유가 없어요
Thank you for worrying about me so much
너무 걱정해주셔서 감사해요
But internal culture improvement plans will continue
하지만 내부 문화 개선 계획은 계속될 것입니다.
If it makes you unhappy, then I apologize
기분 나쁘셨다면 사과드립니다
I didn’t expect you to be so ignorant of the significance of the internal culture improvement plan.
내부 문화 개선 계획의 중요성을 이렇게까지 모르고 계실 줄은 몰랐습니다 .
i feel very disappointed
나는 매우 실망감을 느낀다
You said this plan only costs money and does no good at all?
이 계획은 돈만 들고 아무 소용이 없다고 했죠 ?
What is your so-called company’s position?
소위 회사의 입장은 무엇입니까?
good
좋은
What position are you referring to?
어떤 입장을 말씀하시는 건가요?
I'm just worried
걱정이 될 뿐이야
Then you should lead the internal culture improvement plan.
그렇다면 내부 문화 개선 계획을 주도 해야 합니다 .
That's not what I should do
그건 내가 해야 할 일이 아니야
good
좋은
I see
알겠어요
Then Director Chen
그렇다면 첸 감독은
Please don't do anything
제발 아무것도 하지 마세요
I'll take the lead, you don't have to do anything
내가 앞장설 테니 넌 아무것도 할 필요 없어
Understand?
이해하다?
Chief
실장
how?
어떻게?
It's not like I said something I shouldn't have said , and I'm qualified to say that.
해서는 안 될 말을 한 것도 아니고 , 그런 말을 할 자격도 있다.
Who knows?
누가 알아?
if
만약에
I really became the head of the Strategy Headquarters
정말 전략본부장이 되었어요
Maybe the situation will turn around
어쩌면 상황은 반전될지도 모릅니다
hateful
증오스러운
What did you just say?
너 방금 뭐라고 했어?
you bastard
이 새끼야
Hey, do you think it’s fair to say that the sales team didn’t know anything?
야, 영업팀은 아무것도 몰랐다고 하는 게 옳다고 생각해?
Senior, please sit down first and then talk
선배님 먼저 앉아서 얘기 좀 해주세요
- Sit down first. - Let go, you brat.
- 먼저 앉으세요 - 놔, 이 새끼야.
Otherwise, do you want us to die together?
그렇지 않으면 우리가 함께 죽기를 바라나요?
We are just acting according to the plan proposed by the public relations office.
저희는 홍보실에서 제안한 계획대로 행동하고 있을 뿐입니다.
Oh my god
맙소사
Hello
안녕하세요
What did you say in the beginning?
처음에 뭐라고 하셨어요?
Have you ever said that you want to target
타겟팅하고 싶다고 말한 적이 있나요?
Already listed high-protein companies to start?
이미 상장된 고단백 기업을 시작하시겠습니까?
That's how newbies like us who know nothing do things like that, you brats!
우리같이 아무것도 모르는 초보들이 그런 짓을 하는 구나 , 이 새끼들아!
There's a bit of a misunderstanding here
여기에는 약간의 오해가 있습니다.
We could have proposed it
우리는 그것을 제안할 수도 있었어
But it is up to the PR team to decide what approach to take
하지만 어떤 접근 방식을 취할지는 PR팀의 몫입니다.
Yeah?
응?
So you’re going to do this trick now?
그럼 이제 이 트릭을 수행하시겠습니까?
- I really want to hit you - So just leave it alone.
- 정말 때리고 싶어 - 그러니까 그냥 놔두세요.
The main ones are three groups.
주요 그룹은 세 그룹입니다.
That's Leader Chi's business
그건 치 리더의 일이야
Why are you more excited than them?
왜 그들보다 당신이 더 흥분합니까?
There's no need for everyone to die together, right?
모두가 함께 죽을 필요는 없잖아요 ?
You... Hey, Zhenrui
너... 안녕, 젠루이
Yes, senior
응, 선배
I'm telling you, that's not how the PR team works.
내가 말하는데, 홍보팀은 그런 식으로 일하지 않는다.
We are not like your business groups who are divided into different groups just to compete with each other.
우리는 단지 서로 경쟁하기 위해 서로 다른 그룹으로 나누어지는 귀하의 비즈니스 그룹과 같지 않습니다 .
Our Digital PR Team and News Media Team
디지털홍보팀과 뉴스미디어팀
Like gears that have to fit together to work, you bastard
서로 맞아야 작동하는 톱니 바퀴 같은 놈아
Do you understand?
이해했나요?
We're in this together, brat
우리는 함께 이 일을 하고 있어, 친구
But there is still a person in charge, so just leave it alone.
하지만 아직 담당자가 있으니 그냥 놔두세요.
Zhao Zhenrui, you stinky boy
Zhao Zhenrui, 이 냄새나는 소년
You eat these and then leave to feed them. Take this by the way.
이것을 먹고 나서 먹이를 주러 가세요.
senior
상위
Chi Hyo
치효
Please take a look at this too
이것도 좀 봐주세요
I changed the design a little bit
디자인이 조금 바뀌었어요
Are you going home?
집에가는거야?
Want to give you a lift?
당신을 태워주고 싶나요?
up to you
당신한테 달렸습니다
It seems you can't write it yet
아직 못 쓰시는 것 같네요
Let's go to dinner, I'll treat you
저녁 먹으러 가자, 내가 대접해줄게
What's wrong with you?
왜 그래?
I see you have been pulling your hair just now
방금 머리를 당기고 있는 걸 보니
Go get some nutrition
가서 영양 섭취하세요
What do you want to eat?
너 뭐 먹고 싶니?
Ginseng chicken soup? eel?
인삼삼계탕? 뱀장어?
Or raw beef?
아니면 생고기?
It's really hard for me to treat you to dinner
당신에게 저녁 대접하기가 정말 힘들어요
So you don’t have to be polite and try to choose the more expensive one, understand?
그러니 예의를 갖추어 더 비싼 것을 선택하려고 할 필요는 없습니다 . 이해하셨나요?
I want to eat roasted pork rinds
돼지껍데기 구워먹고싶다
Hey, you can eat that kind of thing anytime
야, 그런 건 언제든지 먹어도 돼
Let's go to that store
그 가게로 가자
A famous roasted pork rind restaurant that only company bosses go to.
회사 상사들만 가는 유명한 돼지껍데기 전문점.
Let's go eat too
우리도 먹으러 가자
Hey, it's a different matter if you go to that place.
아, 그 곳에 가보면 얘기가 달라진다.
good
좋은
Yes, represents
네, 나타냅니다
yes
예
I'm fine
잘 지내요
real
진짜
good
좋은
Are you talking about Representative Xu?
Xu 대표를 말하는 건가요?
So is he still in the company?
그럼 그 사람은 아직 회사에 있는 걸까요?
Okay, I'll do my best too
알았어 나도 열심히 할게
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
Jae Min, I'm sorry, let's go eat there next time
재민아 미안해 다음에 거기 먹으러 가자
Do you want to go to Global Broadcast?
글로벌 방송에 참여하시겠습니까?
Is Representative Xu there?
Xu 대표님 계시나요?
I heard he was working overtime all night to save Ang's bakery.
앙의 빵집을 구하기 위해 밤새 야근을 했다고 들었어요.
It seems better if I go there to buy something.
거기 가서 뭔가를 사면 더 좋을 것 같아요.
Just let me get off the bus in front. I'll take a taxi there.
버스 앞에서 내리게 해주세요. 거기서 택시를 탈게요.
Hey, I've already driven you here, why are you taking a taxi? Just let me drive you
야 내가 이미 여기까지 데려다줬는데 왜 택시를 타는데? 그냥 운전하게 해주세요
But it's the opposite direction
그런데 반대방향이네
yes
예
Is my friend a good person?
내 친구는 좋은 사람인가?
Come
오다
You don't have to buy these
이런거 사지 않아도 돼
Didn’t I tell you to replenish your body?
내가 네 몸에 보충하라고 말하지 않았느냐?
This eel sushi is delicious
이 장어 초밥 맛있어요
I just feel like I'm very grateful to you. After all, I let you fly for dinner.
나는 당신에게 매우 감사하다고 생각합니다. 결국 저녁 식사를 위해 비행기를 타게 해주었습니다.
I also bought my share.
나도 내 몫을 샀다.
You go in quickly
너 빨리 들어가라
Okay, then I'm leaving
알았어 그럼 난 갈게
goodbye
안녕히 가세요
Well, Jacob
글쎄, 제이콥
Thank you for letting us photograph your company's facilities
귀사 시설 사진을 촬영할 수 있게 해주셔서 감사합니다
of course
물론
High protein bread for our main customers
주요 고객을 위한 고단백 빵
Is using your company’s products
회사 제품을 사용하고 있습니다.
So we can…
그래서 우리는 할 수있다…
Emphasize the high quality of your company’s ingredients
회사 재료의 높은 품질을 강조하세요.
OK, I will send you the final version before publishing it.
알겠습니다. 게시하기 전에 최종 버전을 보내드리겠습니다.
Thanks, bye
고마워요, 안녕
You are here
당신은 여기에 있습니다
Representative Xu
쉬 대표
Ang's Bakery uses ingredients that are the UK's number one highest in protein
Ang's Bakery는 영국에서 단백질 함량이 가장 높은 재료를 사용합니다.
So I contacted the local shooting team and planned to shoot a video and put it on the video platform
그래서 현지 촬영팀에 연락해서 영상을 촬영해서 영상플랫폼에 올리기로 했어요
It is also expected to upload an introductory article about the product’s history, taste and quality.
제품의 역사와 맛, 품질 등을 소개하는 글 도 게재될 예정이다 .
This is how we plan to save Ang's bakery
이것이 우리가 앙의 빵집을 구할 계획인 방법입니다
Hope this can help you too
이것이 당신에게도 도움이 되기를 바랍니다
Thank you
감사합니다
Is there anything I can do to help?
제가 도와드릴 수 있는 일이 있나요?
let me see…
좀 보자…
(eel sushi)
(장어 초밥)
The food in this restaurant is delicious
이 식당 음식은 맛있어요
Let's eat first and then talk
먼저 먹고 얘기하자
You haven't had your meal yet?
아직 식사 안 하셨나요?
yes
예
No wonder my stomach keeps pounding
이상하지 않게 배가 계속 쿵쿵거린다.
So hungry
너무 배고프다
Yun Zhao, are you full?
윤자오, 배불러요?
right
오른쪽
Then I can...
그럼 난 할 수 있어...
OK, you eat it
응, 너 먹어.
good
좋은
(Ang’s Bakery)
(앙스 베이커리)
(Zhang bento full of mother’s sincerity)
(어머니의 정성이 가득한 장도시락)
Representative Xu
쉬 대표
Just say it after you have eaten.
식사 후에 말씀해주세요.
No, I have a bigger stomach, so I eat twice as much as others.
아니요, 저는 위가 커서 남들보다 두 배나 많이 먹습니다.
You do not know?
넌 몰라?
your body is in denial
네 몸이 거부당하고 있어
But that's what I thought
하지만 난 그렇게 생각했어
I'll eat with you, as much as you want
너랑 같이 먹을게, 네가 원하는 만큼
But you'd better not eat any more
하지만 더 이상 먹지 않는 게 좋을 거야
OK, I won't eat
응, 안 먹을 거야
Hey, you really don’t want to eat?
야, 너 진짜 먹기 싫은 거야?
I don't like eating eels, it's disgusting
장어 먹는 걸 별로 안 좋아해서 역겹다
So why should you buy it? You probably don't want to buy me something to eat.
그렇다면 왜 구매해야 할까요? 당신은 아마 나에게 먹을 것을 사주고 싶지 않을 것입니다.
bingo
빙고
I just want to buy you something to eat
그냥 먹을 것 사주고 싶은데
Still pretending
아직도 그런 척하고 있어
Anyway, thank you
아무튼 감사 해요
what is that? Why do you take it so seriously?
저게 뭐에요? 왜 그렇게 심각하게 받아들이나요?
These two are the same product
이 둘은 같은 제품이에요
But the ingredient analysis table is different
하지만 성분분석표는 다릅니다
What?
무엇?
(Ingredient analysis table)
(성분분석표)
This means one of them is fake
그 중 하나가 가짜라는 뜻이에요
what are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
Hello
안녕하세요
Where have all the previous guests gone?
이전 손님들은 다 어디로 갔나요?
have no idea
전혀 모른다
There is a channel owner with millions of subscribers
수백만 명의 구독자를 보유한 채널 소유자가 있습니다.
Gave a very negative review
매우 부정적인 리뷰를 작성했습니다.
Said this is a boring place that makes you want to vomit
여기가 토하고 싶을 정도로 지루한 곳이래
I guess that’s life, right?
그게 인생인 것 같아요, 그렇죠?
If there is an uphill slope, there will be a downhill slope.
오르막길이 있으면 내리막길이 있기 마련이다.
Hello
안녕하세요
The tears you shed seem to be full of blood
네가 흘린 눈물은 피로 가득 찬 것 같아
Right?
오른쪽?
Hello? I'm Yoo Jae-min
안녕하세요? 저는 유재민이에요
Hello, factory manager
안녕하세요 공장장님
Yes, please wait a moment
네, 잠시만 기다려주세요
- Hello
- 안녕하세요
You're bored without any guests. Would you like me to make you a cocktail?
손님도 없이 심심하시군요. 칵테일 만들어 드릴까요?
Can you make cocktails?
칵테일을 만들 수 있나요?
Don't look at me like this. I used to be a part-time cocktail maker.
그런 눈으로 보지 마세요, 저는 칵테일 메이커 아르바이트를 했었거든요.
Although the boss later handed over the store to me and left, leaving me unable to show my talents.
나중에 사장님이 저에게 가게를 넘겨주고 떠나셨기 때문에 저는 제 재능을 발휘할 수 없었습니다.
I usually wait in front of someone else’s house.
나는 주로 남의 집 앞에서 기다린다.
Either a lover who is currently dating or a lover who has broken up.
현재 사귀고 있는 애인이든, 헤어진 애인이든.
How is it here?
여긴 어때요?
Why is it so messy and scary?
왜 이렇게 지저분하고 무서운 걸까요?
Because this place is about to be rebuilt
이곳은 곧 재건축될 예정이기 때문에
So didn’t I tell you not to come here?
그럼 내가 여기 오지 말라고 하지 않았나?
You forced yourself to come here
억지로 여기까지 오셨군요
Because I feel really depressed
기분이 정말 우울하니까
Depressed to the point of going crazy
미칠 정도로 우울하다
Even after drinking, I still feel scared all the time
술을 마셔도 늘 겁이 나
Sister Yunzhao, wouldn't you do this?
윤자오 자매님, 이러지 않겠습니까?
"Sister Yun Zhao"?
"자오 윤 자매"?
Did you just call me sister?
방금 나한테 언니라고 불렀어?
Yes, I really want to call you that now
응, 지금은 꼭 그렇게 부르고 싶어
Okay, please do as you please
알았어, 맘대로 해라
me
나
I went to the hospital today
오늘 병원에 갔어요
This is the boss mentioned in the message board article
게시판 글에 언급된 사장님이십니다
The one in hospital
병원에 있는 사람
I heard his condition is very bad
그의 상태가 매우 안 좋다고 들었는데
So you went to see him?
그래서 그를 만나러 갔나요?
I haven't gone yet
아직 안 갔어
what do I do?
나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
I…
나…
I really just want to perform well
난 정말 연기를 잘하고 싶을 뿐이야
You are very proud of yourself in the company
당신은 회사에서 자신을 매우 자랑스럽게 생각합니다
Discuss with the two team leaders over there
저기 있는 팀장 두 분과 의논하세요
Makes me feel jealous
질투심을 느끼게 해
so
그래서
I think I can do it too
나도 할 수 있을 것 같아
I want to hear others say that even though I am just a newcomer
신인인데도 그런 말을 듣고 싶어요.
But really capable
근데 진짜 능력있네
But I really didn't expect it to be like this
그런데 정말 이렇게 될 줄은 몰랐다
I mean it
진심이야
Sister Yun Zhao
자오 윤 자매
what do I do?
나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
Where did Agent Park go?
박요원은 어디로 갔나요?
In the director's office
원장실에서
(report)
(보고서)
(I am the person in charge of online promotion of Senteng 100 high protein milkshake )
(저는 센텡 100 고단백 밀크쉐이크 온라인 홍보 담당자 입니다 )
(Solely determines and conducts all viral marketing)
(모든 바이럴 마케팅을 단독으로 결정하고 수행함)
Do you think this is the most efficient method?
이것이 가장 효율적인 방법이라고 생각하시나요?
Negative marketing tactics?
부정적인 마케팅 전략?
- Right - Isn't that your own popular product?
- 그렇죠 - 그거 본인의 인기상품 아닌가요?
Because now the place where I belong is Seyong
이제 내가 속한 곳은 세용이니까
Then you should know better than anyone else
그렇다면 누구보다 당신이 더 잘 알아야겠죠
Products that are popular on social platforms
소셜 플랫폼에서 인기 있는 제품
How easy it is to ruin something using social platforms
소셜 플랫폼을 사용하여 무언가를 망치는 것이 얼마나 쉬운가요?
right
오른쪽
Did you report to the team leader?
팀장에게 보고하셨나요?
- No - The team leader didn't know?
- 아니 - 팀장이 몰랐어요?
She gave me full authority so I didn't report to her again.
그녀는 나에게 모든 권한을 부여했기 때문에 나는 다시는 그녀에게 보고하지 않았습니다.
Is this what you did at Cao Ya Public Relations?
이것이 당신이 Cao Ya Public Relations에서 한 일인가요?
Is this Park Yoon-soo's way of doing things?
이게 박윤수의 행동인가?
It seems I saw the wrong person
사람을 잘못 본 것 같네요
I understand
이해합니다
you can go out
넌 나갈 수 있어
you temporarily
당신은 일시적으로
Put down all business
모든 사업을 내려놓고
Stop working and reflect.
일을 멈추고 반성하세요.
OK
좋아요
Director Goo, we are going in.
구국장님, 들어가겠습니다.
I haven't reported it to the director yet . I'm embarrassed by your behavior.
아직 원장님께 보고도 안했는데 당신의 행동이 부끄럽습니다.
You report to her now
너 지금 그 사람한테 보고해
I told you not to do this
내가 이러지 말라고 했잖아
It doesn't matter
그것은 중요하지 않습니다
Hello
안녕하세요
Is there a problem?
문제가 있습니까?
The promotion of protein powder this time
이번에는 단백질 파우더 프로모션
This is a promotional method that Seyong has used many times before.
이는 세용이가 이전에도 여러 번 사용해왔던 홍보 방식이다.
Yes, after operating on social platforms, our PR Team 2 will send the news to the media
네, 소셜 플랫폼 운영 후 저희 홍보2팀이 해당 소식을 언론에 보내드립니다.
reuse news
재사용 뉴스
Promote on social platforms
소셜 플랫폼에서 홍보
This is something Park cannot do alone.
박 대통령 혼자서는 할 수 없는 일이다.
I also think that the third PR team should not be held responsible.
제3홍보팀도 책임을 져서는 안 된다고 생각합니다.
You mean this is the responsibility of the entire PR office?
이게 홍보실 전체의 책임이라는 겁니까?
right
오른쪽
But it’s not just the PR office
하지만 홍보실만 그런 건 아니죠
The sales team should also be responsible
영업팀도 책임져야 한다
We've had dozens of meetings together
우리는 수십번의 회의를 함께 했습니다.
Their position is that no matter what method is used , as long as the product can be sold well
어떤 방법을 사용하더라도 제품이 잘 팔릴 수만 있다면 좋다는 게 이들의 입장이다.
as you said
당신이 말했듯이
This is fake
이건 가짜 야
Yes, that's right
네, 맞습니다
But the custom here is to do this kind of thing
그런데 이곳의 관습은 이런 일을 하는 것입니다
It's no big deal
별거 아니야
That's how Shi Rong is
시롱이 그렇군요
I'm not saying that the PR team is not at fault.
홍보팀의 잘못이 없다는 말은 아니다.
only
오직
I'd say it's not just the PR team's fault.
단순히 홍보팀만의 잘못은 아니라고 말하고 싶습니다.
that
저것
Regarding the overall low moral sense of the company
회사의 전반적인 낮은 도덕성에 대하여
I deeply agree
나는 깊이 동의한다
About this time
이 시간쯤
The new person in charge of the case and her superior agent
사건의 새로운 책임자와 그녀의 상급 대리인
As well as the team leader responsible for supervision , the public relations office and the sales team
감독을 담당하는 팀장 과 홍보실, 영업팀을 비롯해
Everyone should apologize and take responsibility
모두가 사과하고 책임을 져야 한다
I don't think any one person should be responsible
어느 한 사람이 책임을 져야 한다고는 생각하지 않습니다.
No matter that person is Agent Park
그 사람이 박요원이건 간에
still you
아직도 당신
Team leader
팀 리더
When I came back from the team leader meeting, I didn't expect that you were already there.
팀장 회의를 마치고 돌아왔을 때 당신이 이미 거기에 있을 줄은 몰랐습니다.
This is fraud, it's all lies
이건 사기야 다 거짓말이야
anyway
그래도
You were really loyal and said it was all your own doing.
당신은 정말로 충성스러웠고 모든 것이 당신 자신의 일이라고 말했습니다.
If it happens to our group
만약 우리 그룹에 그런 일이 일어난다면
They will definitely say that it was me who instigated it.
그들은 그것을 선동한 사람이 바로 나였다고 분명히 말할 것입니다.
because that's the truth
그게 진실이니까
Why do you want to ruin such a beautiful atmosphere?
왜 이렇게 아름다운 분위기를 망치려고 하는 걸까요?
But where did Team Leader Cui go?
그런데 추이 팀장은 어디로 갔나요?
He said he was nervous
긴장했다고 하더라구요
Got diarrhea
설사를 했어
He is really unhelpful at all.
그는 정말 전혀 도움이 되지 않습니다.
I was so moved that I wanted to cry
너무 감동해서 울고 싶었어요
The team leaders all came to help me speak.
팀 리더들이 모두 와서 제가 말하는 것을 도와주었습니다.
They are so loyal
그들은 매우 충성스럽습니다
Too
도
This is what the public relations teams of large companies all do.
대기업 홍보팀이 다 하는 일이다.
The people in the group are like brothers and sisters
그룹의 사람들은 형제 자매와 같습니다.
I always feel
나는 항상 느낀다
I'm incompatible with their kind of relationship.
나는 그들의 관계와 호환되지 않습니다.
but
하지만
Today I feel like I belong there too
오늘 나도 거기에 속해 있는 것 같아
I am grateful to those who have helped me
나를 도와준 사람들에게 감사하다.
especially you
특히 당신
You helped me a lot this time
이번에 많은 도움을 받았어요
It gave me courage and gave me a lot of support
나에게 용기를 주고 많은 응원을 줬어요
You don't have to be so grateful
너무 감사할 필요는 없어요
because
왜냐하면
You behave well and are a good person so everyone will help you
당신은 행동도 잘하고 좋은 사람이어서 모두가 당신을 도와줄 거예요
Thanks
감사해요
I didn’t see you in the office today either
오늘도 사무실에서 못 봤어
Where are you?
어디세요?
Golf driving range? Why go there?
골프연습장? 왜 거기로 가나요?
I don't know why I'm here either
나도 내가 왜 여기 있는지 모르겠어
The actual owner of the PF factory is the owner of this golf driving range
PF공장의 실제 주인은 이 골프연습장의 주인입니다.
But I didn't see him all day
하지만 하루종일 그를 보지 못했어요
what does it mean? PF factory?
무슨 뜻이에요? PF공장?
PF？
PF?
"Pat Leightford"
'팻 레이트포드'
Raw material supplier of Serong Protein Powder?
세롱 단백질분말의 원료 공급업체는?
you know?
알잖아?
I remember the name of the company because it was Pirate Food.
해적식품이라 회사 이름을 기억해요 .
I mean, changing your name is too casual, right?
이름을 바꾸는 건 너무 당연한 일이잖아요?
Hello, Team Leader Ko Dong-kyun
안녕하세요, 고동균 팀장님
so what?
그래서 뭐?
- You're here. - What are you doing there?
- 여기 있잖아 - 거기서 뭐하는 거야?
haven't seen you for a long time
오랫동안 당신을 보지 못했어요
- Hello
- 안녕하세요
Hey, wait a minute
잠깐만요
Team Leader Gao
가오 팀장
Agent Liu
리우 요원
Please go in first
먼저 들어가주세요
Are you playing golf too?
골프도 치시나요?
Do you come to this golf driving range often?
이 골프연습장에 자주 오시나요?
Is this place run by Team Leader Zhao’s brother-in-law or brother-in-law?
이곳은 자오팀장의 처남이 운영하는 곳인가요, 아니면 처남이 운영하는 곳인가요?
Team leader Cho Jin-seo of the medical care team?
의료팀 조진서 팀장?
Yes, this is close to my home, so I come here often
응, 여기 집 근처라서 자주 와요
You also know that Team Leader Zhao is the king of matchmaking.
자오 팀장이 매치메이킹의 왕이라는 것도 알고 계시죠?
If I want to please him, of course I have to come often.
그를 기쁘게 하고 싶다면 당연히 자주 와야 합니다.
Yes, that's right
네, 맞습니다
You are so ignorant
당신은 너무 무지하다
That you're busy
바쁘다고
good
좋은
Hello? Feel sorry
안녕하세요? 유감
Is Team Leader Zhao’s brother-in-law or brother-in-law the boss of PF?
자오팀장의 처남인가 아니면 처남이 PF의 사장인가?
It seems so
그런 것 같아요
- What are you doing? - Talk to you later
- 뭐하세요? - 나중에 얘기하자
I'll tell you everything later
나중에 다 말해줄게
I'll close the line first
먼저 줄을 닫을게요
Hello, Li Haizhao
안녕하세요 리하이자오님
pick it up
그것을 집어
Don't throw away cigarette butts, pick them up
담배꽁초 버리지 말고 꼭 챙겨가세요
I asked you to pick it up
뽑아달라고 했더니
Is that okay?
괜찮나요?
where are you going?
어디 가세요?
I don't want to go home
집에 가고 싶지 않아
Damn it, that guy is here again
젠장, 그 사람이 또 왔어
Wearing weird pajamas and going crazy with mom
이상한 잠옷을 입고 엄마랑 뒹굴뒹굴
Really annoying
정말 짜증나
Can't we move out?
우리 이사 가면 안 돼요?
Are you making money?
당신은 돈을 벌고 있습니까?
We live separately from my mother
우리는 어머니와 따로 산다
how?
어떻게?
Don't you want to live with me?
나랑 같이 살고 싶지 않아?
Don't sleep at a friend's house
친구 집에서 자지 마세요
You must come back tonight or send me a message
오늘 밤에 다시 오시거나 나에게 메시지를 보내주세요
Brother Zhejun
제준 형제
- What's wrong? - Why did you come out so slowly?
- 뭐가 문제 야? - 왜 이렇게 천천히 나왔나요?
Wait, let's go outside and talk
잠깐, 밖에 나가서 얘기하자
- Why? - let's go
- 왜? - 갑시다
What else are you doing? Come here quickly
또 뭐하는거야? 빨리 여기로 와
that…
저것…
- What? - Those things
- 무엇? - 그것들
What? There's nothing, let's go
무엇? 아무것도 없어 가자
(Amino acid score of Senteng 100 high protein milkshake : 64 points)
(센텡 100 고단백 밀크쉐이크의 아미노산 점수 : 64점)
Are you dating?
데이트 중이신가요?
my ex-wife
내 전처
What?
무엇?
The ingredient analysis table given by Team Leader Song is fake
송팀장이 제시한 성분 분석표는 가짜다
right
오른쪽
The ingredient analysis table I commissioned from another research institute
타 연구기관에 의뢰한 성분분석표
Shows that it does not meet the standards of the Food and Drug Administration
식품의약품안전청 기준에 부합하지 않음을 나타냅니다.
I also visited the factory today
오늘도 공장을 방문했어요
The actual situation is so bad that there is no quality assurance under normal procedures.
실제 상황이 너무 나빠서 정상적인 절차에서는 품질 보증이 없습니다 .
But that manufacturer
그런데 그 제조사
Are you a relative of Team Leader Zhao?
자오 팀장의 친척이신가요?
Hello, Team Zhao...
안녕하세요, 자오팀...
Can Team Leader Zhao do such a thing by himself?
자오 팀장이 혼자서 그런 일을 할 수 있을까요?
Absolutely impossible
절대 불가능
So which level is involved?
그렇다면 어떤 수준이 관련되어 있습니까?
Team leader Song is 100% involved
송팀장이 100% 참여
Plus…
을 더한…
Any more? What else?
더 이상 없나요? 또 뭐야?
The former supplier's boss passed away unexpectedly last month.
전직 공급업체 사장이 지난달 갑작스럽게 세상을 떠났다.
Because we changed the supplier, the boss gave up on himself and drank all day long...
공급자를 바꿨다고 사장님이 포기하고 하루종일 술을 마셨는데...
do not talk
말 하지마
Only you know about this, right?
이건 너만 아는 거 맞지?
If this matter spreads, our world...
이 일이 퍼지면 우리 세상은...
It’s really going to be doomed, you know?
정말 망할 거야, 알지?
(Se Yong)
(세용)
I hope the internal culture improvement program can be accelerated
내부 문화 개선 프로그램이 더욱 가속화되길 바랍니다.
The current plan is temporarily suspended
현재 계획은 일시적으로 중단됩니다
Why?
왜?
This is an instruction from above
위에서 지시한 내용입니다
Start over
다시 시작하다
- Okay - Regarding the internal culture improvement plan in the future
- 네 - 향후 내부 문화 개선 방안에 대해
Just follow my instructions
그냥 내 지시를 따르세요
No matter what anyone above says, ignore it.
위에 누가 뭐라고 하든 무시하세요.
OK
좋아요
Even if I have to leave this company
이 회사를 떠나더라도
I will also do a complete employee survey
또한 전체 직원 설문조사도 실시하겠습니다.
Make improvement plans before leaving
떠나기 전에 개선 계획을 세우세요
Director Gu
구 이사
Come on
어서 해봐요
(Ministry of Social Affairs, "Daguo Daily")
(사회부, '대구일보')
How was the report?
보고서는 어땠나요?
After putting more emphasis on the vendor selection process
벤더 선정 과정을 좀 더 강조한 후
Just send it out again
그냥 다시 보내세요
- I understand, okay. - Thank you for your hard work.
- 알겠습니다. - 수고해 주셔서 감사합니다.
Please enjoy
즐기세요
Feel sorry
유감
I didn't mean to see it
볼 생각은 아니었는데
But after seeing it, I couldn’t ignore it
그런데 보고 나니 무시할 수가 없었어요
After I read the ingredient analysis table of protein powder,
단백질분말의 성분분석표를 읽어본 후,
Just dig into this matter with Senior Ma
마 선배와 함께 이 문제를 파헤쳐 보세요.
I want to remind you to be prepared
준비하라고 상기시켜드리고 싶어요
The news will be reported soon
그 소식은 곧 전해드리겠습니다
maybe that's a good thing
어쩌면 그게 좋은 일일지도 몰라
Pus is going to flow out
고름이 흘러나올 것 같아요
Only then will everyone know that the suppuration is so serious
그래야만 화농이 심각하다는 것을 모두가 알게 될 것입니다.
(2022 Seoul Global Business Sustainability Forum)
(2022 서울 글로벌 비즈니스 지속가능성 포럼)
(Business sustainability, today’s future)
(경영의 지속가능성, 오늘의 미래)
(Seoul Global Business Sustainability Forum)
(서울글로벌비즈니스지속가능성포럼)
- Nice to see you again - Nice to see you
- 다시 만나서 반가워요 - 만나서 반가워요
It’s been a long time since the last forum
지난번 포럼 이후 오랜만이네요
Yes, that's right
네, 맞습니다
so nice to see you again
다시 만나서 너무 반가워요
Alas, Representative Lin
아아 린 대표님
Hello, minister
안녕하세요 장관님
- Nice to see you here - Me too
- 여기서 만나서 반가워요 - 저도요
I've heard a lot of news
소식을 많이 들었어요
When you think of corporate sustainability in the future, will you think of Shi Rong?
미래의 기업 지속가능성을 생각할 때 시롱(Shi Rong)을 떠올리시겠습니까?
That’s why I hired an expert in corporate sustainability to serve as chief public relations officer.
그래서 저는 기업 지속 가능성 전문가를 고용하여 최고 홍보 책임자로 일했습니다.
- I'm Goo Yi Jung - I know
- 저는 구이정이에요 - 알아요
She is a well-known figure in the field of corporate sustainability
그녀는 기업 지속 가능성 분야에서 유명한 인물입니다.
I saw a lot of big bosses coming
큰 상사들이 많이 오는 걸 봤어요
I heard that the president of Macquarie International is going to give a keynote speech
맥쿼리인터내셔널 회장님이 기조연설을 하신다고 들었습니다.
right
오른쪽
Director Goo, you need to take a look at this
구 감독님 이거 좀 보셔야 해요
(Is Shi Yong not related to the death of the boss of a certain outsourcing company ?)
(시용은 특정 외주업체 사장의 죽음 과 관련이 없는 걸까요?)
(This newspaper reported on the selection process of Serong’s raw material suppliers in July )
(본 신문은 지난 7월 세롱의 원자재 공급업체 선정 과정을 보도했다.)
(suspected of fraud)
(사기 의혹)
Representative Lin
린 대표
Representative Lin Zhixian
대표 임지현
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
Excuse me
실례합니다
Representative, it's time for us to go.
대표님, 이제 갈 시간입니다.
The problem of Shi Rong bullying others has been reported again
Shi Rong이 다른 사람을 괴롭히는 문제가 다시보고되었습니다.
How do you explain it?
어떻게 설명하나요?
Do you really practice corporate sustainability well?
정말로 기업의 지속가능성을 잘 실천하고 있나요?
Excuse me
실례합니다
Minister, I'm sorry.
장관님, 죄송합니다.
- Let's go. - Wait, Representative Lin.
- 가자 - 잠깐, 린 의원님.
- Sorry - Representative Lin
- 죄송합니다 - 린 대표님
Sorry, Secretary Kim.
죄송합니다, 김비서님.
Representative Lin Zhixian!
임지현 대표님!
Representative Lin!
린 대표님!
It happens to be today
오늘이 되는군요
It just happened to be today!
마침 오늘이 되었네요!
It's really embarrassing and has been thrown to the whole world.
정말 부끄러워서 전 세계에 던져졌습니다.
I will investigate this matter thoroughly
이 문제를 철저히 조사하겠습니다.
Do you have to keep your mouth shut?
입을 다물고 있어야 합니까?
Nothing done at all?
전혀 아무것도 하지 않았나요?
Are you going to always disappoint me like this?
너 자꾸 이렇게 날 실망시킬 거야?
Don't rely too much on me as your backer.
당신의 후원자로서 나를 너무 의지하지 마십시오.
Because it may collapse overnight
밤새 무너질 수도 있으니까
Go quickly!
빨리 가세요!
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Did she leave you?
그녀가 당신을 떠났나요?
Need a car?
차가 필요하세요?
Do you want me to drive you?
내가 당신을 운전해주기를 원하시나요?
Just go your own way
그냥 네 길을 가거라
Don't make trouble
문제를 일으키지 마세요
It seems you are not as powerful as I thought
생각보다 넌 그렇게 강력하지 않은 것 같아
so what?
그래서 뭐?
disappointed?
실망한?
No, I'm glad you're not that good
아니, 네가 별로 좋지 않아서 다행이야
I am leaving
저 이제가요
(Is Shi Yong not related to the death of the boss of a certain outsourcing company ?)
(시용은 특정 외주업체 사장의 죽음 과 관련이 없는 걸까요?)
(Reporter Choi Hye-young)
(최혜영 기자)
Reporter Cui Huiying is your college classmate, right?
최희영 기자는 대학 동기 맞죠?
Did you provide her with the information?
그녀에게 정보를 제공했나요?
How did she know this?
그녀는 이것을 어떻게 알았습니까?
Does this concern you?
이것이 당신과 관련이 있습니까?
Can I ask you something?
뭐 좀 물어봐도 될까요?
- Hello - You have nothing to do with this?
- 안녕하세요 - 당신은 이 일과 아무 관련이 없나요?
- What did you say? - If you didn't hear, then I'll ask again.
- 뭐라고 하셨나요? - 못 들으셨다면 다시 질문하겠습니다.
Team leader
팀 리더
You and this protein powder incident
너와 이번 단백질가루 사건
No connection at all?
전혀 연결이 되지 않나요?
What are you talking about?
무슨 얘기를 하는 건가요?
How dare you blur the focus?
어떻게 감히 초점을 흐리게 합니까?
It's me asking you a question!
내가 당신에게 질문을 하고 있어요!
Are you the source of reporter Choi Hye-young’s information?
최혜영 기자의 정보 출처는?
The source is indeed me
출처는 바로 저입니다
Hello!
안녕하세요!
you…
너…
You are from the public relations team of Se Yong
세용홍보팀입니다
You should be the first to stop this!
이 일을 가장 먼저 막아야 합니다!
I won't let you go
나는 당신을 보내지 않을 것입니다
Brace yourselves, you bastard
정신차려라 이 새끼야
Have you seen people complaining about side effects of taking protein powder?
단백질 파우더 복용으로 인한 부작용에 대해 불평하는 사람들을 본 적이 있나요 ?
Interviewed on TV?
TV에서 인터뷰를 했다고?
What is the purpose of the Se-yong Public Relations Office?
세용홍보실의 목적은 무엇인가요?
You can't stop the news and you can't clean up the mess.
뉴스를 멈출 수도 없고 혼란스러운 상황을 정리할 수도 없습니다.
What to do now?
이제 무엇을 해야 할까요?
The situation is very bad
상황은 매우 나쁘다
No, Team Leader Zhao...
아니, 자오 팀장...
Director Chen
첸 감독
yes
예
You have been the head of the public relations office for decades
당신은 수십년 동안 홍보실장을 맡아왔습니다.
You have a good mind
당신은 좋은 마음을 가지고 있습니다
Why do you think there is a saying that "crisis is an opportunity"?
위기는 기회라는 말이 왜 있다고 생각하시나요 ?
I heard Team Leader Song say
송팀장님 말씀을 들었습니다.
The reporter who wrote this story is a friend of our PR office staff
이 기사를 쓴 기자는 우리 홍보실 직원의 친구입니다.
The source of the report comes from that employee
보고서의 출처는 해당 직원에게서 나옵니다.
Relate that employee to an employee previously mentioned on the message board
해당 직원을 이전에 메시지 보드에서 언급한 직원 과 연결합니다.
Let’s convene a personnel committee
인사위원회를 소집하자
Since they made a mistake, we should hold them accountable
그 사람들이 잘못한거니까 책임을 져야지
It would be better if they could hand in their resignation letters.
사직서를 제출할 수 있으면 더 좋을 것 같습니다.
Put all the blame on the PR office?
모든 책임을 홍보실에 전가하시겠습니까?
right
오른쪽
nice
멋진
Then let the chief public relations officer, the head of the public relations office, be dismissed from his post.
그러면 홍보실장인 홍보실장을 직위에서 해임시키십시오 .
Then Representative Lin will naturally be hit hard.
그러면 린 대표는 당연히 큰 타격을 입을 것이다.
In this case
이 경우
We can stop hearing about damn corporate sustainability for a while
우리는 한동안 기업의 지속 가능성 에 대한 이야기를 듣지 않을 수 있습니다
As expected
예상대로
The brilliant idea devised by the head of the future strategy headquarters
미래전략본부장의 기발한 아이디어
If we strike first to gain strength, Zheng Shouhuan will no longer be our opponent.
우리가 먼저 공격해 힘을 얻으면 정수환은 더 이상 우리의 상대가 될 수 없습니다.
Right?
오른쪽?
(Announcement on the second convening of the Personnel Committee)
(제2차 인사위원회 소집 공고)
Personnel committee?
인사위원회?
Although it’s not a bad thing to get rid of the people below first...
아래 사람을 먼저 없애는 것도 나쁘지는 않지만...
( The following personnel committee will be convened in accordance with Paragraph 3 of Article 10 of Serong Company Regulations )
( 세롱 사규 제 10 조 3 항에 의거 아래와 같이 인사위원회를 소집합니다 )
(Convening date: November 3, 2022. Convening location: Large conference room on the third floor of the head office)
(소집일자 : 2022년 11월 3일. 소집장소 : 본사 3층 대회의실)
(Targets: Yoo Jae-min, Public Relations Team 2 Park Yoon-so, Public Relations Team 3)
(대상 : 유재민, 홍보2팀, 박윤소, 홍보3팀)
(Personnel record sheet, name: Park Yun-soo)
(인사기록부, 이름 : 박윤수)
(Personnel record sheet, name: Liu Caimin)
(인사기록부, 이름: 유채민)
sit down
앉아
Let's get started
시작하자
About PR Team 2 Agent Yoo Jae-min
홍보2팀 유재민 요원 소개
Acted by Park Yun-soo of PR Team 3
홍보3팀 박윤수 님이 맡았습니다.
The Personnel Committee will now be held
이제 인사위원회가 개최됩니다
Subtitle translation: Wu Jingyi
자막 번역: 우징이